<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Get-Type on RoosTech</title>
    <link>http://blog.roostech.se/tags/get-type/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Get-Type on RoosTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 14:14:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.roostech.se/tags/get-type/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Powershell script: Write object to SQL</title>
      <link>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/powershell-script-write-object-to-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 14:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/powershell-script-write-object-to-sql/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I was playing around with PowerShell, gathering information from a lot of servers and I felt that I needed to have a simple way of storing that information in a database. I could have written my own T-SQL statements for creating the tables and then do the inserts in the powerShell scripts I was playing around with. But that felt like it would just take time so I started to think about a function that would just accept any object and do the magic of creating a table and then inserting anything I piped to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get-Type alternative for $null values</title>
      <link>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/get-type-alternative-for-null-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 14:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/get-type-alternative-for-null-values/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes its useful to get information about object properties in PowerShell. You might be writing a script where you want to extract information from a series of objects and you need to know what data type a property contains. Often this is not a big problem since you can use the GetType function that most objects have.
Then you run in to the problem that I had recently: You expect a series of objects and you check the types on the properties and suddenly a few of them doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the function GetType for some reason.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
