<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hyper-V on RoosTech</title>
    <link>http://blog.roostech.se/tags/hyper-v/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hyper-V on RoosTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 14:14:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.roostech.se/tags/hyper-v/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resources for RemoteFX in Windows Server 2012</title>
      <link>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/resources-for-remotefx-in-windows-server-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 14:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/resources-for-remotefx-in-windows-server-2012/</guid>
      <description>While playing around with my lab machine and writing my previous two posts I found that there are not that much information to be found about RemoteFX in Windows Server 2012 so I thought that I would collect some good links on the subject. Most of the information I could find on TechNet is about Windows Server 2008 so some of the links below are from blogs elsewhere. I would also like to note that the focus here is on using RemoteFX for multimedia and using a virtual GPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDP 8.0 for Windows 7 SP1</title>
      <link>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/rdp-8.0-for-windows-7-sp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 14:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/rdp-8.0-for-windows-7-sp1/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago Microsoft finally announced that they will be releasing Remote Desktop Protocol 8.0 for Windows 7 SP1. Earlier it was not clear if this would be released for Windows 7 or if RDP 8.0 would be exclusive for Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012. RDP 8.0 should give some proper improvements when it comes to hardware accelerated graphics in Hyper-V with the RemoteFX capabilities. Among many improvements there are some new compression algorithms which will lower the bandwidth needed for RDP sessions where some parts of the screen might use a different algorithm compared to other parts, and even mixing UDP and TCP on different parts of the screen depending on what&amp;rsquo;s displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving RemoteFX performance in Hyper-V</title>
      <link>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/improving-remotefx-performance-in-hyper-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 14:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/improving-remotefx-performance-in-hyper-v/</guid>
      <description>As I wrote earlier its possible to run RemoteFX on some of the slowest GPU´s you can buy today (on a regular CPU actually), but you might not get the performance you need to get anywhere. This time I will go through some of the options you have for getting it to work a bit better. Keep in mind that I am writing this with a really poor GPU in mind (yes, the Intel HD 2500 is not good for anything else than browsing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure RemoteFX in Hyper-V running Windows Server 2012 with low end GPU</title>
      <link>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/configure-remotefx-in-hyper-v-running-windows-server-2012-with-low-end-gpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 14:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.roostech.se/posts/configure-remotefx-in-hyper-v-running-windows-server-2012-with-low-end-gpu/</guid>
      <description>This is for experimenting with RemoteFX in Hyper-V in a lab environment using Windows Server 2012. I wanted to see what I could do with RemoteFX on a slow GPU. To see how far I could get I started off with the Intel HD 2500, which is built into the Intel Core i5 3550 processor (Ivy Bridge). You can go through these steps with any supported hardware, and you probably get better results if you don&amp;rsquo;t use the HD 2500 as I did.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
